Guide to the Carl E. Ladd Director of Extension papers,1924-1930.
Ladd, Carl E., Director of Extension papers, 1924-1930
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Carl E. Ladd Director of Extension papers, 1924-1930.
21-24-97
Carl E. Ladd
13.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, and other records of Carl E. Ladd as Director of Extension at the New York State College of Agriculture.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Carl E. Ladd was Director of Extension and Dean of the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell.
Carl Edwin Ladd was born 25 Feb. 1888 in McLean, Tompkins County, New York, at the farm of his parents, Arnold D. and Mary E. (Mineah) Ladd; he was their second son and the youngest of three children. Both parents were natives of Tompkins County; his father was descended from Daniel Ladd, who came from England to Massachusetts in 1634. Carl attended local schools and at fifteen entered the nearby Cortland (N.Y.) Normal School, from which he graduated in 1907. After a year as school principal in South Otselic, N.Y., he enrolled in the College of Agriculture at Cornell University. He received a B.S. degree in 1912 but stayed on for graduate study in the department of farm management, specializing in cost accounting under the direction of Prof. George F. Warren, whose economic ides he was to share, during the agricultural crisis of the early 1930s. He received the Ph.D. in 1915.
That year Ladd became director of the New York State School of Agriculture at Delhi, one of six regional schools recently established to provide a two year program in applied agriculture. In 1917 he assumed overall direction of the six schools as specialist in agricultural education in the State Education Department at Albany. Two years later, he became director of the State School of Agriculture at Alfred, N.Y. Ladd returned to Cornell in 1920, as extension professor of farm management. He was made director of extension work for the College of Agriculture and the College of Home Economics at Cornell in 1924.
Carl Ladd’s career was build upon identification with the interests of New York agriculture. He regarded the extension service as a vehicle for transmitting the needs of the farmer to the college and as an agency for formulating research programs to meet those needs. As director of extension he worked closely with the State Farm Bureau Federation, using its county units as local bases of operation for the College of Agriculture; through this structure extension specialists were made available to individual farmers for consultation. Under Ladd, Cornell also continued its policy of aiding farmer cooperatives such as the Dairymen's League.
In 1932 Ladd became dean of the colleges of agriculture and of home economics and director of the agricultural experiment station at Cornell. A skilled administrator and mediator, he set up meetings at the college between farmers and the businessmen who supplied their needs. Recognizing the trend toward specialization in agriculture, he altered the focus of extension work from general farming to particular commodities. He also kept Cornell in the forefront of agricultural research, concentrating on such problems as better food packaging, dehydration, and the artificial breeding of livestock. He set up a special interdepartmental research and extension projects designed to expand the market for potatoes, an important state product, and encouraged the development of the frozen food industry in New York State.
Ladd's influence in agricultural matters extended beyond the campus. He had become widely known to the farming public at large through the columns of the "American Agriculturist," edited by his close friend Edward R. Eastman. Sensitive to the techniques of public relations, he maintained contacts in Albany and Washington and with the newspaper publisher Frank Gannett. Ladd served as secretary of the State Agricultural Advisory Commission under Gov. Franklin D. Roosevelt, and later as chairman; he became chairman of the New York State Planning Council in 1936; and he was a director of the Federal Land Bank at Springfield, Mass., a major source of credit for Northeastern farmers.
Ladd's reaction to the agricultural program of the New Deal was ambivalent. He supported the Agricultural Adjustment Act as a temporary expedient and recognized the need for some government assistance, but objected to the degree of central planning envisaged by the Roosevelt administration. As new federal agencies concerned with the farmer were created, Ladd sought with considerable success to have them administered by the existing network of county agents that made up the extension service of the various land-grant colleges. The matter was formalized at a conference in 1938 between representatives of the colleges and the federal Department of Agriculture at which a compromise (the "Mount Weather Agreement") was worked out by Ladd.
While still active as dean, he died on 23 July 1943 of a coronary attack at the age of fifty five and was buried at McLean, New York.
Gould P. Colman, Dictionary of American Biography, 1973.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports, and other records of Carl E. Ladd as Director of Extension at the New York State College of Agriculture.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ladd, Carl E.; New York State College of Agriculture.
Subjects:
Agricultural extension work--New York (State).; University extension--New York (State).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
See also Carl E. Ladd papers, #21-2-87.
CONTAINER LIST
- Subject matter files, 1924-1925
  - County Appropriations (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Extension Service Conference - Montgomery Robinson (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conference Specialists (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Monthly Extension Conference (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Conference - Northeast Directors Extension - M. S. McDowell (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Replies to Circular Letter #7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Better Sires Campaign (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reforestation Conference - C. R. Pettis, E. H. Thomson, R. S. Hosmer, G. F. Warren, J. Coryell, C. A. Taylor (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Regional Conferences (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Publications - Cornelius Betten (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Extension Service News - Editorial Board (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Extension Methods (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Forestry Policy (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Committees in Extension Specialist Group - S. Sanderson, E. L. Worthen, M. Van Rensselaer, W. T. Crandall, G. W. Peck (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Marginal Forms (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - State-Wide Extension Program (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fairs (State and County) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Farmers Week [including one L. H. Bailey letter, Program] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Harvest Weather Forecast (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Laws (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clarke-McNary Act (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Memoranda (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Community and County Programs (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Radio - C. B. Smith (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Professional Improvement of Agents and Staff (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Spray Service (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Weather Bureau Forecasts (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, 1924-1925
  - A (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Agricultural Society (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Atwood, Prof. M. V. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - American Agriculturist - E. R. Eastman (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Farm Bureau Federation (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - B (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Burritt, M. C. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - C (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dairymen's League Cooperative Association - Charles Tuck (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Dairymen's League News - D. J. Carter (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Dairymen's League Situation (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Directors of Extension - John D. Willard (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - E (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - F (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Farm Bureau Federation - E. V. Underwood (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
  - Farrand, Pres. Livingston (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Federal Land Bank (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Federated Fruit and Vegetable Growers - A. R. Rule, General Manager (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - G (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Getman, A. K. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - G.L.F. [Grange League Federation] Exchange - H. E. Babcock (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Grange State - S. L. Strivings, Natalie C. Barnes (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - H (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Home Bureau Federation - Mrs. G. Thomas Powell (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Hopper, Prof. H. A. (Animal Husbandry) (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Hotels (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - I (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - J (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - K (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - L (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Land Grant College Association (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - M (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Moore, Dr. V. A. (Veterinary) (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - N (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - National Dairy Show - W. E. Skinner (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - New York Canning Crops. Association Inc. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - New York Seed Improvement Cooperative Association Inc. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - New York Sheep Association - H. E. Robertson (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - O (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - P (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Potash-Marl - John B. Gleason (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Pyrke, Berne A. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Q (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - R (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Railroads (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Rochester Exposition (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rural New Yorker - H. W. Collingwood (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - S (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - State Schools (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - T (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Telegrams (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - U-V (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - X, Y, Z (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Federal, 1924-1925
  - Bureau of Public Roads (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Office of Cooperative Extension Work - H. M. Dixon (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Secretary of Agriculture - Henry C. Wallace (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Extension Work on Forestry - G. H. Collingwood (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Agricultural Economics Circulars - census, etc. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Crop Estimates (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Plant Industry (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - States Relations Service - H. W. Hochbaum (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Goddard, L. H. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lloyd, W. A. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural Economics - H. M. Dixon (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - United States Department of Agriculture (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Smith, C. B. (Box 2, Folder 23-25)
  - Smith, C. B. - Reports (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - True, Dr. A. E. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Department of Agriculture - Florence E. Ward (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Warburton, Director C. W. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Wilson, M. C. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Department of Farms and Markets (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Department of Education (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Secretary (University) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Mann, A. R. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Betten, Dr. Cornelius (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Thatcher, Director R. W. (Research) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Secretary (Agriculture College) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Appointments and Resignations in Counties (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Appointments and Resignations at Colleges (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Faculty (Agricultural) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Agricultural Economics and Farm Management (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Agricultural Library (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Agronomy (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Animal Husbandry (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Dairy (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Entomology (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Extension (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Extension - P. L. Dunn (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
  - Extension - Prof. Montgomery Robinson (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Extension - Prof. R. H. Wheeler (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Extension Publications - Bristow Adams (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Extension (Reading Course) - Prof. H. A. Stevenson (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Extension - County Agent Leaders - J. Coryell (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Extension - Prof. W. J. Wright (Box 2, Folder 55-56)
  - Extension - Circular Letters (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Extension - C. E. Ladd (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Home Demonstration Agents Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - County Club Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - County Agriculture Agents - Counties A-Z (Box 2, Folder 61-64)
  - Forestry Department - Joshua A. Cope (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Home Economics - Ruby G. Smith (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Home Economics - Prof. Martha Van Rensselaer (Box 3, Folder .2-3)
  - Plant Breeding (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Plant Pathology - M. F. Barrus (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Pomology - G. W. Peck (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Poultry - J. E. Rice (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Rural Engineering (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Rural Social Organization - Prof. R. A. Felton (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Vegetable Gardening - E. V. Hardenburg (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Farrand, President Livingston (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Appointments and Resignations at College - Helen G. Titus (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Betten, Cornelius (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - International Education Board - A. R. Mann (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Thatcher, R. W. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Business Office (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Purchasing Department (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - University Faculty (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural Economics and Farm Management (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Hart, V. B. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Myers, W. I. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Warren, G. F. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Agronomy (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Animal Husbandry - Montgomery Robinson (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Plant Physiology (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Dairy Industry (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Ross, H. E. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Entomology (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Administration (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Western Trip (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bates, E. A. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Administration - Crosby, D. J. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Administration - Montgomery Robinson (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Administration - Wheeler, R. H. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Committee in Agriculture - Daniel P. Witter (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Circular Letters (College) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Extension Circular Letters (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Appointments and Resignations in Counties - A. R. Mann (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Co-Agent Leaders Office - J. Coryell (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Co-Agent Leader's Office - E. A. Plansburgh (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Co-Agent Leader's Office - L. S. Simons (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Co-Agent Leader's Office - C. A. Taylor (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Farm Bureau Circular Letters (Box 3, Folder 43-44)
  - Junior Extension - W. J. Wright (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Junior Extension - P. R. Young (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Stevens, Mildred (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Publications - Bristow Adams (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Publications - D. S. Cook (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Farm Study Course - G. S. Butts (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Publications - H. A. Stevenson (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Farm Practice (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Porter, J. P. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Hosmer, R. S. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Extension Forester - J. A. Cope (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Forestry (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Plant Breeding (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Plant Pathology (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Barrus, M. F. (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Poultry (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Poultry - J. E. Rice (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Palmer, E. L. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Rural Engineering - B. B. Robb (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Rural Social Organization - R. A. Felton (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Sanderson, D. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Counties A-C (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Counties D-H (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Counties J-N (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Counties O (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Counties P-S (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Counties S-Y (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - County Club Agents (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - County Home Demonstration Agents (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - College of Home Economics - Claribel Nye (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Van Rensselaer, Martha (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Smith, Ruby G. (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Music (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Milk Situation (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Other States (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Professional Improvement (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Special Provisional Improvement Course (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Projects (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Radio (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Reforestation (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Rodent Control (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Educational Policies and Methods in Extension (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - State Wide News Sheet (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Better Bull Train (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Special Potato Train (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Junior Extension-Thanksgiving Programs (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Annual Conference (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Extension Service News (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Publications Committee (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Education Policy and Methods (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Farmers Week, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Farm Relief Legislation (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Federal Compensation (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Loan Library Letter (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Child Labor Amendment (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Alfalfa Campaign (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cow Culling Service (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - County Vocational Education and Extension Board (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Home Economics Extension Conference (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Extension Specialists Conference (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Annual Conference (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - Junior Agents Conference (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Northeastern Directors Conference (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Demonstration Train New York Central (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - A (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - American Agriculturist - Henry Morganthau, Jr. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - American Agriculturist - E. R. Eastman (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - B (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
  - Burritt, M. C. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - C (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Camp Vail (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - D (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Dairymen's League News (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Dairymen's League Cooperative Association (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - E (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - F (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Farm Bureau Federation, American (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - New York Farm Bureau Federation - Victor E. Underwood (Box 4, Folder 42-45)
  - Farm Economia Association (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Federal Land Bank (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - G (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Getman, A. K. (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Gillett, R. L. (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - G. L. F. Exchange (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Grange - state (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - H (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Hotels (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Home Bureau Federation (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Hobson, Asher (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - International Educational Board (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - J (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - K (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - L (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Land Grant College Association (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Mc (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - M (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Letters of Recommendation for Positions (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Mo (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - N (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - New York Agriculture Society (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - New York Food Marketing Research Council (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - New York Vegetable Growers Association (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - New York State Sheep Growers Cooperative Association (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - New York Seed Improvement Association (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - New York Cooperative Seed-Potato Association, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - New York State Guernsey Breeders Association, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - O (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - P (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - R (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Railroads (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Rural New Yorker - H. W. Collingwood (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - S (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Saxton, Mrs. Sarah C. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sheffield Farms Co. Producers (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Symons, T. B. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - State Schools (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Stevenson, H. A. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - T (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Telegrams (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - U - V (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - University Secretary (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - W (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - X, Y, Z (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Secretary of Agriculture - W. M. Jardine (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bureau of Agricultural Economics (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Bureau of Public Lands (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Secretary of Agriculture - W. M. Jardine (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Bureau of Agricultural Economics (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Bureau of Public Roads (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Bureau of Entomology (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Warburton, C. W. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Ward, Florence E. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Hochbaum, H. W. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Extension Service General (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
  - Smith, C. B. (Box 5, Folder 26-27)
  - Wilson, M. C. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Reports (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Use of Frank (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Apple Marketing Problems (Box 5, Folder 31-33)
  - B. W. D. Testing (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Capper-Ketcham Bill (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Regional Conferences - Department - Act, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Special Conference Co. Agents (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Dynamometer (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Extension Specialists Conference (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Conference - Northeastern States (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
  - Relations Committee - Extension Agents (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Potato Committee (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Extension Service News Board (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - European Corn Borer Control (Box 5, Folder 45-47)
  - Farmers Week - Feb. 7-13, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Annual Conference (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Feed Stores (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Gasoline Tax (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Horse Questionnaire (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Milk Situation (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Fluid Milk Situation (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - International Education Board (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Professional Improvement (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Reforestation - Connecticut Hill (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Reforestation (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Radio (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - County Agents Annual Report (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - State Fair (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Traveling Exposition (N.Y.C.R.R.) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Meat Livestock Train (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Adirondack Forestry Tour (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Teaching (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - University Secretary (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Geneva Experiment Station - R. W. Thatcher (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Mann, Dean A. R. (Box 6, Folder .10-11)
  - Appointments and Resignations in Counties (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Appointments and Resignations in College (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Purchasing Department (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Business Office (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Betten, Acting Dean (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Agricultural Economics and Farm Management (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Agronomy (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Animal Husbandry (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Dairy Industry (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Entomology - C. R. Crosby (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Administration (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Ladd, C. E. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Expense Account - C. E. Ladd (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Bates, E. A. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Crosby, D. J. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Kirkland, J. B. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Wheeler, R. H. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Extension Service (Miscellaneous Correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
  - Smith, C. B. (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Director of Extension - C. W. Warburton (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Ward, Miss Florence E. (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Hochbaum, H. W. (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Graham, A. B. (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Clarke-McNary Appointment (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Payroll (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Federal Trade Commission (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Tariff Commission (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Robinson, Montgomery (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Emley, Anna May (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Witter, D. P. (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Narrative Summary - Field Extension Service (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Extension Circular Letters (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - County Agent Leader (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Farm Bureau Circular Letters - J. Coryell (Box 6, Folder 46-47)
  - Wright, W. J. (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Junior Extension - Circular Letters (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Adams, Bristow (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Butts, G. S. (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Ham, L. P. (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Forestry (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Home Demonstration Agents (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Plant Pathology (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Plant Breeding (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Pierstorff, A. L. (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Pomology (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Poultry (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Rural Education (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Rural Engineering (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Rural Social Arg. (Box 6, Folder 63)